# Alvssa Anderson

Visual Designer ~ Web Developer ~ User Experience ~ Graphic Designer ~ User-Interface Professional Alyssaanderson432@gmail.com • 470-216-8258 • https://www.linkedin.com/alyssa-true-poet

### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS:**

Seasoned professional with a diverse creative background. Completing a web development degree in December 2024. Specific expertise in graphic design and clothing templates. Excels in connecting with clients and building strong professional relationships. Solid foundational knowledge in interactive communication, building user interfaces, and web page development.

Web Development: Languages: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Web Design Tool: Bootstrap, Canva

Development Tools: VSCode, Netbeans, Codepen, Penpot

Design and Modeling: Adobe: Illustrator, Photoshop & InDesign, Figma

Software Proficiency: Microsoft Office & Outlook, Google Workspace

#### **EDUCATION:**

Raritan Valley Community College, Branchburg, NJ

Associate of Applied Science: Interface Design and Web Development | Graduation: December 2024

**GPA: 3.8** 

Related Coursework: Web Development 1, Java Programming, Interactive Multimedia, JavaScript, User and Interface Programming, Interface Design and Human-Computer Interaction, Visual Design 1, Web Development II

#### **PROJECTS:**

#### Web Development I | Fall 2023

### About Me Website -

Created a functioning website that highlights some things about myself. Independently coded the website choosing the color schemes, layout, and shared content within the site utilizing VS Code, CSS, HTML https://aboutme-lyssama.netlify.app/

# Visual Design I | Spring 2024

#### Project I

Designed a logo and identity system inspired by a mythological figure utilizing Adobe Illustrator. Solely sketched and designed all elements, then created them digitally. https://docs.google.com/document/d/17vbnWNtf8ivoz97ItczshIZHFt0arOKMTzx4c 5 GLI/edit

### Project II:

Created a poster to raise awareness for a social, economic, political, ethical or cultural topic of choice. Designed a social awareness poster centered on mental health in the workplace utilizing Adobe InDesign. https://docs.google.com/document/d/1tZ9nthPPb9qaY5r 9EaIxy39x2gUKrZEAUqaLLAZzE4/edit

Created a readable layout that informs the audience of a designated time period from the history of Graphic Design. Used Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator to create a layout from the Abstract Expressionism of Graphic Design.

# Interface Design & Human Computer Interaction | Spring 2024

#### Project I

Using Penpot, created a High fidelity prototype of a car rental app which allows renters to 1. Scan a OR code without waiting in line to receive their vehicle, and 2. Helps users locate nearby gas stations for convenient refuel before returning the car.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

#### Licensed Barber - ClipDart (locations throughout NJ) | 2023 - present

Company's mission is to improve people's mental health by providing free haircuts. Cultivate strong customer relationships, resulting in a consistent client base and positive reviews.

### Graphic Designer - True Poet LLC (virtual) | 2023-present

Created clothing designs for a company whose mission is to integrate poetry with fashion. Design sketch, cut and sew patterns and use Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator). Recognized for collaborative problem solving.

https://docs.google.com/document/d/1FXj8x3i5BHFL3p-hvVXKOc\_QeeecnAdIhCq8WjWlgLE/edit?usp=sharing

# Licensed Barber – Frank & Sons Barbershop, Dunellen, NJ | 2021 – 2022

- Managed appointment scheduling. Greeted clients, ensuring a welcoming and professional atmosphere.
- Completed Barber Certificate Program at Innovate Salon Academy in South Plainfield, NJ

**VOLUNTEER WORK: Goats of Anarchy Animal Shelter | 2023**